Isaac Chavez

Houston, Texas 77095 | 281-935-5556 | isaac-chavez.com | isaacgc0596@gmail.com | Github | Medium | Linkedin

Full-stack Software Engineer

Full-stack software engineer with experience in JavaScript/JS frameworks and server side architecture, in based programming and the implementation of Object-oriented programming. Self-motivated and possession of strong skills in critical thinking/problem solving, with an interest in how things work in unison, that helps when working with both server side and client-side languages, allowing myself to gain a better understanding and to experiment with different methods/ solutions to solve complex problems. Skills to see the big picture in terms of people, places, and needs, without compromising small details when working in a fast-paced environment, as well as collaborate/communicate well with others as a team to meet deadlines.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, SASS, NodeJs, Python

Frameworks/Database: Rails, Express, React, NextJS, Redux, ActiveRecord, JSON, SQL/PostgreSQL, MongoDB **Methodologies:** Object-oriented programming(OOP), Test-Driven Development, REST Apis, MVC, DRY, Scrum/Agile, Testing/Debugging, NPM, Git, Browser developer tools, Structure, Exterior design, Autocomplete, Scripting language

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Chatter - Github MongoDB, Express, ReactJs, NodeJS (M.E.R.N) Material UI

Users are able to search and join/leave rooms, create rooms, view members, send/edit/delete messages

- Used socket.io for real time, for all changes across all users(c.r.u.d messages, online activity, leave/join rooms)
- See visibly of user when they are online & when they log off to signal other users who are online & login/signup auth
- Be able to edit messages and delete messages from only the current user who deleted it
- Implementation of react hooks for proficiency and guicker rendering

Take A Trip - Github | Demo Ruby, Rails, ReactJs, Redux, TripadviserApi, WeatherApi, Ant and Material UI Users are able to plan trips out by searching for various things to do around their location, and may also add other users to join in on the trip to plan out more ideas

- Used Redux as a way to save state and to be accessible across different pages of the app allowing less conflict and creating a single source of truth
- Used different APIs to be able to gather data from various locations to make a more dynamic website, as well as an API to gather data on the weather for the user's location
- Able to utilize frameworks to style/design the frontend and give more functionality towards the website
- Used only functional components to be able to better understand hooks and being able to implement them

Shoptastic - Github | Demo Ruby, Rails, ReactJs, TargetApi, GoogleApi, React Bootstrap, Semantic UI

E-commerce website where users can search by categories for various items and be able to purchase them, edit their cart and view store locations

- Used an API to gather different sets of products based on a users choice making it more dynamic
- Able to use Google Maps API to lookup store locations as well as a users input for locations in their area
- Used a React Bootstrap and Semantic Ui frameworks to design website
- Create different route pages for a more dynamic website

EXPERIENCE

CrouchJump
Full-Stack Web Developer (P.E.R.N)

Remote/Houston, Texas 10/2020 - Present

- Assist team to develop and implement modular components, with typescript features, keeping codebase DRY
- Work with redux tool-kit to handle global state for ease of access of data between components
- Build api endpoints/tables to proficiently query data to be served to the client
- Collaborate with team to discuss best practices to increase productivity and efficiency in an agile environment

Watson Grinding & Manufacturing

Houston, Texas

Abrasive Blaster/HVOF Operator

03/2017 - 02/2020

- Maximizing workflow and production by preparing parts by masking and blasting so that it may be ready to be applied with a coating
- Set up parts and write programs for which the robot may complete by recording sizes and dimensions, apply carbide
 coating, make sure gun is running smoothly by adjusting gas levels and repairing the gun parts for better
 performance, prolonging the life of hardware therefore saving and reducing company cost
- Good troubleshooting skills, ability to multitask, and good time management, consequently improving manufacturing

EDUCATION

Flatiron School
Full Stack Software Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program
Maybe Creek HighSchool
High School Diploma

Houston, Texas 03/ 2020 - 06/2020 Houston, Texas 06/ 2016